Owen Adrian

Professional software engineer with a 7-year streak of composing robust and intuitive web solutions. Experienced in Ruby on Rails, C#, and React, along with extreme programming practices, Agile, Kanban, and test-driven development.

Mesa, AZ · (816) 944-0745 · me@owen.codes · owen.codes

Technical Skills

- Languages: Ruby (Rails, Sinatra), JavaScript (React, Svelte, Express.js), C#, Java, Python (Flask, FastAPI), CSS (Bootstrap, Tailwind), HTML
- Databases: PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB
- Cloud Platforms: Azure (App Service, Kubernetes), AWS (EC2, S3)
- Tools: Git, GitHub, Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, Heroku, CI/CD

Experience

Lead Software Engineer Syntreno

Aug 2023 - Present

- Designing a Ruby on Rails application and API for managing, processing, and embedding documents for retrieval-augmented generation for GPT.
- Independently developed and licensed a sales training application in Unity.

Software Engineer, Web

Unity Technologies

Mar 2021 - Jun 2023

- Implemented SSO and data providers in a React front-end and ASP.NET backend for importing third-party annotations from Autodesk, Procore, and Jira.
- Spun off microservices for file transformation to speed up job runtime by 90%.
- Containerized a Ruby on Rails app for on-prem deployment by the US Army Corps of Engineers to aid in reconstructing Tyndall Air Force Base.

Full Stack Developer

VisualLive

Mar 2020 - Mar 2021

- Maintained a Ruby on Rails codebase, wrote unit tests with RSpec, implemented CI/CD with GitHub Actions, and managed infrastructure on Azure.
- Used Bootstrap in front-end refactoring to optimize mobile user experience.
- Advised non-technical teams and developed custom CRM (Bitrix24, Salesforce) integrations for clients and marketing and sales teams.

Web Developer, Founder

Order Coffee Online

Sep 2017 - Mar 2020

- Developed an online ordering system in Ruby on Rails that processed over
 \$500,000 in sales from 3 cafes and made the mornings of over 3,000 customers.
- Led shareholder meetings to plan conceptualization and commercialization,
 refine project goals with product feedback, and develop marketing strategies.

Education

Technology Solutions

Northland CAPS

Aug 2017 - May 2018